Uttam Kumar

Software Engineer +91 9354255831 | uttammca1041@gmail.com

Summary

Sr. Software Engineer with over **5 years** of experience in designing and developing sync and async distributed systems, solving business and tech problems involving large scale traffic and data. Well aware about application software SDLC and system designs.

Technical Skills

Languages C#, .Net, MVC, .Net Core, ADO.Net, Entity **Databases** SQL, PostgreSQL **Developer and Cloud Tools** Git **API and Interfaces** RESTful Interfaces, API Development

Scripting Languages ASP.NET, HTML, CSS, jQuery, JavaScript **Development Environment** Visual Studio 2008\15\22

Experience

Team HR GSA Pvt Ltd - Software Developer

Mar. 2023 - Present

Client: - Dish TV India Limited

- · Watcho is an OTT app- based video streaming platform. Allows users to stream Hindi movies, live news, live TV channels, original shows, web series, and short films among others.
- Implemented web Api's for data extraction and manipulation for OTT app service
- Authenticating via token authentication and generating a service-to-service token.
- Api's included functionalities for creation, modification and extraction of various business operations for OTT app related business entities.

Tech stack- C#, .NET Core, Web API, SQL Server

Velocis Systems Pvt, Ltd - Software Developer

May 2022 - Dec 2022

Client: - NIC

- The Delhi Jal Board constituted under the (DJB) Government Departments, Corporate offices
- · Developed and designed responsive websites using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Asp.net, PostgreSQL, C#, resulting in a 25% increase in user engagement

Tech stack- C#, Asp.net Web Form, PostgreSQL, java script, jQuery

Cybex Exim Solution - Developer

Nov 2021 - Apr 2022

- Export and Import Business Data Intelligence Report Application
- · These reports are collated from the actual shipping and customs documents like Bill of Lading, Shipping Bills and Bill of Entries

Tech stack- C#, MVC, SQL Server

COSMOPOLITAN ADVISORY SERVICES Pvt, Ltd - Software Developer

May 2019 - Nov 2021

- Customer Relation Management is method for managing an organization connection with present and potential client.
- It requires making use of technology to organize, automate, and synchronize sales, marketing, customer service, and technical support
- · Designed effective solutions using custom configurations to meet specific client needs

Tech stack- C#, Asp.net Web Form, SQL Server

Prosix InfoTech Pvt Ltd - System Executive

Dec 2017 - Feb 2019

- · Support Engineer, evaluating the process flow and handling the entire Payroll processing
- Human Resources Management System application it maintains the list employees including personal details. It allows the concerned authority to enter the details of new employee.
- · Payroll Processing- Viz. Definition of Salary Head, Basic Pay, Allowances, Standard Deductions, Bonus Calculation

Tech stack- C#, Asp.net Web Form, SQL Server

Education

Dr. A.P.J. Abdul Kalam Technical University United Institute of Management (Allahabad) Magadh University BCA R.L.S.Y College (Aurangabad) 2011 - 2014